&gt；&gt；演讲者1：好奇像JSDoc或
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: Curious what the role of something like JSDoc or
其他符号标准是。
other notation standards are.
听起来有点像是为机器编写代码的问题
It kinda sounds like there's the issue of writing code for the machine and
然后为那些必须在几周后阅读的人类编写代码。
then writing code for the humans who have to read it weeks down the road.
我对使用显式强制的争论非常有说服力，
And I'm very persuaded by the arguments about using explicit coercion,
但你有没有遇到过其他的情况
but are there other cases where you have encountered or
会推荐这样的辅助策略吗？
would recommend ancillary tactics like that?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：嗯，我当然认为如果你从整体上考虑编码，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Well, I certainly think if you think about coding on the whole,
顺便说一下，这是个很好的问题。
it's a great question, by the way.
如果你从整体上考虑编码作为交流我思想的一种方式，
If you think about coding on the whole as a way to communicate my ideas,
然后有很多方法来交流思想。
then there are lots of ways to communicate ideas.
其中一种方法是在您编写的代码中，其中一种方法是在辅助代码中
One of the ways is in the code that you write, one of the ways is in the ancillary
你提到的东西，比如代码注释。
stuff that you mentioned, like for example code comments.
现在有些人告诉你，不，你永远不应该需要代码注释，
Now some people tell you, nah you should never need code comments,
代码应该自己解释。
code should explain itself.
您不应该更多地依赖代码注释而不是代码。
You should not have more reliance upon code comments than the code.
我见过这样的代码库
And I've seen code bases that are like that, that are so
令人费解的是，没有代码注释，没有人会弄明白它。
inscrutable that without the code comment, nobody's figuring it out.
但是代码注释并不是一件可以避免的坏事。
But code comments are not a bad thing to be avoided.
他们没有暴露出这个计划的一些弱点。
They're not exposing some weakness of the program.
这是代码注释的问题。
Here's the problem with code comments.
人们在他们的代码注释中写下了什么，我很抱歉，
People write the what in their code comment, I'm sorry,
他们在代码注释中写下How。
they write the how in their code comment.
就像你有一行写着，I+，和
Like you have a line that says, i++, and
然后你说增量I是代码注释。
then you say something like increment i is the code comment.
我知道它在增加，我看得出来。
I know it's incrementing i, I can see that.
下面是我希望代码注释告诉我的内容，为什么。
Here's what I want the code comment to tell me, why.
为什么你需要增加，为什么只增加1，为什么不增加2或12？
Why do you need to increment, and why only by 1, why not by 2 or 12?
告诉我为什么，有时也许告诉我怎么做。
Tell me why, and sometimes maybe tell me how.
但别告诉我是什么，这就是代码的用途。
But don't tell me what, that's what the code's for.
因此，是的，您可以很好地与您的代码进行通信。
So yes, you can communicate well with your code.
如果您在这个函数上做了一个JS文档，并且说，这两个参数接收
If you did a JS doc on this function and said, these two parameters receive either
字符串或数字，然后你非常清楚地向每个人发出信号，
strings or numbers, then you're very clearly signaling to everybody,
请注意，可能会发生一些强制。
be aware that some coercion may happen.
但它只在字符串和数字之间，所以我们知道
But it's only between strings and numbers, and so we know we
缩小了我们需要关注的角落案件的范围。
have narrowed down the scope of corner cases that we need to be concerned about.
当然，代码注释是有用的，我不会完全依赖它们。
Absolutely, code comments can be useful, I wouldn't rely entirely on them.
我认为在我们的代码中有很多事情可以做得很明显。
I think there's lots of things we can do in our code to be obvious.